Finding Aid for the D. Stanley Tarbell Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
D. Stanley Tarbell Papers
1952-1987
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0430
8.75 linear feet
Biography
D. Stanley Tarbell came to Vanderbilt University in 1967 under the Distinguished Professorship Program, after teaching and chairing the department of chemistry at the University of Rochester for twenty-nine years.
Author of more than two hundred scientific publications, Professor Tarbell completed three degrees in chemistry at Harvard University. He also did post-doctoral work at the University of Illinois.
- Correspondence (one volume) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Copies of Articles (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Introduction (of a book) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- “Roger Adams - The Boston and Cambridge Years. Part 1” By A. T. Tarbell (Box 1, Folder 4)
- “Chemical Labs, Supplies, Instruction, Journals, Women Students, 1876-1913” (Box 1, Folder 5)
- “The Origin of Organic Syntheses” (Box 1, Folder 6)
- C & EN Letters (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Lectures & Seminars, D. S. T. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Personal Correspondence, July, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Element. Org., Lab., Conf. etc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chemistry 135, (1952-53) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Curare Lecture (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Hydrolysis Lecture (Box 1, Folder 13)
- “Development of a Research Laboratory in the Pharmaceutical Industry, 1914-1939” (Box 1, Folder 14)
- “Studies on Polymerization and Synthetic Polymers, 1914-1939” (Box 1, Folder 15)
- A Paper on Hydrogenation (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Notebook - Chemistry, Lowell N-44 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Notebook - Research 1935-36 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Misc. Materials (in a letter-size envelope) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Personal and Family Souvenirs (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Instrumental Revolution (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Reprints and Xerox - Hist. Chemistry (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 4)
- R. A. Lecture and Paper (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Hist. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Venable Paper (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Beckman Lecture and Paper (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Symp. on TN, Chemists (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Graduate Examinations, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Post-Doctorate Correspondence, 1950, July 1958 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Medicinal Chemistry Study Section, To June 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Abbott Laboratories - to, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Speaking Engagements, 1961-64 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Chemistry Department 1947- (Box 2, Folder 15)
- California Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Chemistry 162 (DST) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Personal and Guggenheim, 1961-64 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Chemistry 161-162 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- California - Paper, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Chemistry 131 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Magee Paper (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Classical Organic Chemistry - N. Y. Symp., April, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous, 1950 - July 1958 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- P. 0. Symp, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Abstracts for Conbondale (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Lucas Paper (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Phys Drg. in U.S., 1975-1939 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Whitmore Slides and Papers (Box 2, Folder 29)
- W. A. Noyes Paper, Washington, D.C. (Box 2, Folder 30)
- W. A. Noyes Paper (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Whitmore Symp., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Denicls (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Saccharin Paper (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Arthur Michael Paper (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Arthur Michael & Rachel Lloyd (Box 2, Folder 36)
- W. A. Noyes Paper (Box 2, Folder 37)
- S. F. Acree (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Bob Fuson Papers (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Personal Documents - Graduate School Committee (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Speaking, July 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Org. Div. 6-38431 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- PRF 73-0040, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Abbott Grant (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Journals, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Department - 1969-72 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Department, 1974-Aug. 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous, July 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Jones AIDS Project (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Rec., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Department, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Recommendation, July 1972-74 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Kohler Paper (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Review of Alan J. Rocke’s Book (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Adams ANB (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Roger Adams (Box 3, Folder 16)
- C & EN Review (Box 3, Folder 17)
- ARW Review (Box 3, Folder 18)
- E. Q. Adams (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Seminar, Slides, E. Q. Adams (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Tucson Autobiography (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Lamb Paper (Box 3, Folder 22)
- A. C. Cope (Box 3, Folder 23)
- NSF Roger Adams (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Dudley, Lupton, Fuson (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Kohler ANB (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Lupton (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Adams, final (Box 3, Folder 28)
- J. L. Nef (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Hudson (Box 3, Folder 30)
- American National Biography (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Research Grant, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Personal, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Postdoc and Graduate Student Files, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Recommendations, Sept. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- ABMPS (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Journal Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Personal, Sept. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Current, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- I. W. Papers (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Misc. Records of Biographies (Box 3, Folder 41)
- “Carl S. Marvel at Illinois Wesleyan,” - Paper (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Beckman Center, NAS (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Marvel Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Marvel Reprint (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Chemistry 224 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Reports and Comments, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Marshall Scholarship Committee (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Chemistry 223 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Lectures - Chemistry 220 B (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Personal, July 1972-74 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Spenser - Kellogg - Lectures (Box 4, Folder 7)
- NAS, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Chemistry 224 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Natural Science 101 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Personal Letter to Graduate Students, 1968-71 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Move to Vanderbilt, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Recommendations, Oct. 1, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Nomination of Arnold Beckman for the 1989 Priestley Medal (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Walter Reed, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- NSF, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Centennial Fellows Program (Box 4, Folder 18)
- NIH, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Graduate Students, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Grant Awarded Materials (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Lectures in History of Organic Chemistry (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Mixed Anhydridge Lectures (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Clarence King Paper (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Oxonium Lecture and Notes (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Antinospectarin Lecture (Box 5, Folder 5)
- PPB Prize (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Symp on Textbooks and Teaching (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Fumagillin Lectures (Box 5, Folder 8)
- “Why the History of Chemistry? - Lecture (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Personal, Department, 1947, Aug. 1951 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Personal, before, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- National Academy Letters (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Personal, July 1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Herty Medal (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Dexter Award (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Personal, 1960-66 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- History of Science Society, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Murray Raney (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Center for History of Chemistry (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Correspondence on History of Chemistry, Oct. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- History of Chemistry Division (Box 5, Folder 21)
- R. A. Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 22)
- R. A. - ACS Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 23)
- R. A. Correspondence, E. HV, Lucile and Students (Box 5, Folder 24)
- History Books Read (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Correspondence - Thackray (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Five Recording Tapes (in a letter-size envelope) (Box 5, Folder 27)
- D. Stanley Tarbell’s Lectures (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous Materials (Box 7)